Morrow Family papers, 1839-1966
Sophia Smith Collection
- Lindbergh, Anne (Morrow)
  - Morrow, Elizabeth (Cutter)
    - Speeches and Writings
      - Speeches
        - National War Fund, Women's Division, last meeting, 6 Dec 1943 (Box 95, Folder 22)
        - Martha Lincoln Draper, 6 Dec 1943 (Box 95, Folder 23)
        - Dr. William Adams Brown funeral, 18 Dec 1943 (Box 95, Folder 24)
        - Englewood Red Cross, 25 Feb 1944 (Box 95, Folder 25)
        - Flora Stone Mather Alumnae Association, 50th Anniversary, 16 Apr 1944 (Box 95, Folder 26)
        - Mrs. Carl Elmore's 25 Anniversary in Englewood church, 19 Apr 1944 (Box 95, Folder 27)
        - NY League of Women Voters, Finance Committee, 19 Apr 1944 (Box 95, Folder 28)
        - "The Place of the Liberal Arts in Post-War Education," Women's University Club, 4 May 1944 (Box 95, Folder 29)
        - National War Fund, 27 Jun 1944 (Box 95, Folder 30)
        - New York War Fund opening, 20 Sep 1944 (Box 95, Folder 31)
        - Englewood Community Chest, 23 Oct 1944 (Box 95, Folder 32)
        - "Women Look at Liberal Education," Bowdoin College Institute on Liberal Education, 8 Dec 1944 (Box 95, Folder 33)
        - Union Club, Cleveland and Dr. Butzer's, Buffalo, 9-10 Apr 1945 (Box 95, Folder 34)
        - "Our Spiritual Heritage," 13 Dec 1945 (Box 95, Folder 35)
        - Cleveland College Club, 7 Jan 1946 (Box 95, Folder 36)
        - Dean Virginia Gildersleeve, National Institute of Social Sciences, 22 May 1946 (Box 95, Folder 37)
        - Inauguration of President Stevenson, Oberlin College, 3 May 1947 (Box 95, Folder 38)
        - "Manners and Morals in an Endowment Campaign," Swarthmore, 23 Jan 1948 (Box 95, Folder 39)
        - Milton Dinner, New York, 21 Apr 1948 (Box 95, Folder 40)
        - "England Revisited," Englewood Women's Club, 1 Nov 1948 (Box 95, Folder 41)
        - "Limits of Freedom," Fortnightly, 29 Nov 1948 (Box 95, Folder 42)
        - "Does a Good Mother Make a Good Grandmother?" Cosmopolitan Club, 8 Feb 1949 (Box 95, Folder 43)
        - Wooster College Golden Anniversary, 12 Dec 1951 (Box 95, Folder 44-45)
        - Prophecy, 1953 (Box 95, Folder 46)
        - "A Grandmother's Fling," Cosmopolitan Club, 3 Mar 1953 (Box 96, Folder 1)
        - "A Tribute to Frederick Duncan," 24 Mar 1953 (Box 96, Folder 2)
        - "Tolerance - Vice or Virtue?" Fortnightly, 16 Nov 1953 (Box 96, Folder 3)
        - "A Mexican Christmas," Englewood Presbyterian Church, 16 Dec 1953 (Box 96, Folder 4)
        - "Hints on Entertaining" to wives of Union Theological Seminary students, 26 Apr 1954 (Box 96, Folder 5)
        - Elisabeth Morrow School Commencement, 11 Jun 1954 (Box 96, Folder 6)
        - 60th Anniversary of Englewood Women's Club, 8 Nov 1954 (Box 96, Folder 7)
        - The Little School 13th Commencement, undated (Box 96, Folder 8)
        - Tribute to Frances Pomeroy, undated (Box 96, Folder 9)
        - Englewood Community Chest first annual meeting, undated (Box 96, Folder 10)
        - Speaking invitations from organizations (Box 96, Folder 11)
        - Notes for speeches, undated (Box 96, Folder 12-13)
        - Smith College Speeches, 1918-49 (Box 96, Folder 14-35)
  - Morrow, Faith: wedding announcement, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Morrow, Jay J. and family: correspondence to ECM, 1903-35 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Morrow, Margot
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - Cutter, Annie Spencer (1877-1957), 1955 (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - Morgan, Constance Morrow, 1939 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter, 1935-54, undated (Box 97, Folder 5-10)
      - Yates, Edith, 1942 (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, incoming, undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Reeve Dr. John Charles
    - Memorial book, 1921 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1883-1913 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - Reeve, Emma Griswold Barlow: memorial book and letter, 1903, undated (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Reeve, Lella: correspondence to ECM, 1902-39 (Box 97, Folder 16-17)
  - Reeve, Mary Sherborn: correspondence to ECM, 1883 (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Reeve, Sidney: correspondence to ECM and writing, 1937-41 (Box 97, Folder 19-20)
  - Scandrett, Agnes: correspondence to ECM, 1901-52, undated (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - Scandrett, Jay M.: correspondence, 1917-53 (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - Scandrett, Mary: correspondence, 1937 (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Scandrett, Richard: correspondence, 1939-54 (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - Spencer, Edwin: correspondence, 1862-64 (Box 97, Folder 25)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - Spencer, Timothy Reeve, 1862-67 (Box 97, Folder 26)
      - Cutter, Annie Spencer (1845-1938), undated (Box 97, Folder 27)
      - Reeve, John C., 1845-64 (Box 97, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1870 (Box 97, Folder 29)
  - Spencer, John, 1892-1914 (Box 97, Folder 30)
  - Spencer, Mary: correspondence, 1867-96 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Spencer, Mary Adams: Our Grandmother by Mary S. Kassick, 1896 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Spencer, Timothy Reeve: correspondence, obituary, photographs, 1859-67 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Spencer, Timothy P.: correspondence to children, 1867-71 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Wilkie, John: correspondence to ECM, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Yates, David and Miles, 1941-54, undated (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Yates, Edith
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - Cutter, Annie Spencer (1877-1957), 1898-1954 (Box 98, Folder 7)
      - Cutter, Annie Spencer (1845-1938) and Charles Long, 1898-1925 (Box 98, Folder 8)
      - Morgan, Constance Morrow, 1925 (Box 98, Folder 9)
      - Morrow, Dwight, 1927 (Box 98, Folder 10)
      - Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter, 1895-54, undated (Box 98, Folder 11-14)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Morgan, Constance Morrow: Milton Academy report card, 1928-1954; Correspondence to ECM (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Morgan, Elisabeth Reeve Morrow: Diplomas, Smith College and Milton Academy; "Elisabeth Morrow's Experiment," Pictorial Review; Correspondence: valentine to AML, 1914-1932
  - Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter
    - Biographical material
      - New Jersey Senate resolution, 18 Mar 1955 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - article, "Die Heilige Elisabeth" undated (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Chart of Childhood and adolescence by Edward P St. John Union Theological Seminary brochure 1954 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Colby College: brochure on campus building undated (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Travel: Mexico (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - "Casa Mañana" article, House and Garden, Dec 1938 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - "The Rivera Murals in Mexico," Vogue, 10 Nov 1930 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - "Cuernavaca," Vogue, 22 Dec 1930 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - "La Casita en Cuernavaca," House Beautiful, Oct 1931 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - "The Cult of the Sun at Zenith in Ancient Mexico," Jul 1930 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - Holiday, Mar 1953 with article on Mexico City (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - Photograph of Diego Rivera mural undated (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - China: Women's colleges: printed material, 1931-47 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - Fred Davis: enclosure of Mexican residence layout, 24 Nov 1941 (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - Z[?], Carl: "The Road to Cuernavaca" illustration undated (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - Dunn, Ruth C., 31 May 1947 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Organizations
      - Community Chest of Englewood printed material and campaign figures, 1934-35 (Box 99, Folder 6)
      - Smith College
        - sketch of bookplate for Morrow House library by Hampshire Bookshop undated (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - SCAN: Smith College Associated News, 6 Nov 1946 (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - Alumnae Fund printed material, 1942 (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - Class of 1896 resolution praising ECM, 1925 (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - 1907 Prize Song, 1940 (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - "Missouri vs. Smith" Life, 9 May 1949 (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - comparison of income versus expenses, 1945 (Box 99, Folder 7)
        - printed material and clippings, 1931-41 (Box 99, Folder 7)
      - United Service Organization: printed material and clippings (Box 99, Folder 8)
      - YWCA: rendering and layout of building in Mexico City, 1929 (Box 99, Folder 9)
        - publicity, 1926 (Box 99, Folder 9)
        - finances, 1922 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Morrow, Dwight Whitney, Jr. (1908-1976) (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Blueprint: Harvard Columbus Expedition schooner 1939 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter
    - Biographical material
      - Clipping: "Jenny Lind Guiding Genius of Kitty Cheatham," Bridgeport Life; illustrated map of Peiping (Beijing), China; citation to ECM: Cleveland Community service society; Cuernavaca house, floor plan, 1929-1954 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Organizations
      - Food for Freedom: New York Post article on food shortages; Welsh Choir, seating chart and dinner list; clipping: "Industrial Mobilization for a Mechanized War" by T.H. Thomas, 1939-1945 (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - Smith College: wallpaper samples from Sophia Smith homestead restoration; chart of housing needs, Smith College; Smith College Association for Christian Work activity list; poster: Mexican market,1916-1950 (Box 100, Folder 4)
      - North Haven, Maine, library: elevations, grading study, plans, H. Daland Chandler, architect 1939-1940 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Writings
      - The Painted Pig: fan mail from children, circa 1930 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: United Service Organizations: scrapbook of news clippings, 1942 (Box 101)
- FLAT FILE
  - Elizabeth Cutter Morrow
    - Biographical materials
      - Birthday card showing "Grandma Bee" and her 12 grandchildren; painting by Reeve Lindbergh undated (Map-case drawer 32)
        - Travel
          - China and Japan: map of Yenching University; map of Japan; Chinese map of Temple of Heaven, Peking; Ming Tombs drawing/map 1936 (Map-case drawer 32)
          - Mexico: interior decoration plan for US Embassy; text insert by Margaret Loring Thomas accompanying map of Mexico 1927-1930 (Map-case drawer 32)
      - Correspondence: annotated map from Ontario trip, enclosed in 26 Aug 1905 from Dwight W. Morrow 1905 (Map-case drawer 32)
      - Organizations
        - Smith College: map of US with fundraising regions with quotas; Sophia Smith homestead; Committee on Furnishing the New Dormitories floor plans 1916, undated (Map-case drawer 32)